Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome to EnglishPod.
欢迎来到EnglishPod。
I'm joined here today with...
今天和我一起的是……
Erika.
Erika。
And my name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And we're going to be looking at an office lesson today.
今天我们要上一节办公室课程。
That's right.
没错。
We've got a lesson about describing somebody who's not such a good employee.
我们有一节关于描述一个不太好的员工的课程。
Right.
对。
So we're going to be talking about how to describe this type of situation and language
所以我们要讨论如何描述这种情况以及相关的语言。
for making your point.
为了表达你的观点。
Yes.
是的。
So let's look at some vocabulary from the dialogue in Vocabulary Preview.
那么，让我们在词汇预览中看看对话中的一些词汇。
So two words today.
今天有两个词。
The first one is a good fit.
第一个是“合适”。
A good fit.
合适。
So when we're talking about an employee and he's a good fit, it means he's suitable for
所以当我们谈论一个员工，说他很合适，意思是他适合
the job.
这份工作。
Yes.
是的。
He's suitable for the job or for the company.
他适合这份工作或这家公司。
For the company, right?
适合这家公司，对吧？
So the opposite would be not a good fit.
所以反义词就是“不合适”。
Exactly.
没错。
The title of today's lesson.
今天课程的主题。
Right.
对。
And our last word for Vocabulary Preview, performance.
词汇预览的最后一个词是“表现”。
Performance.
表现。
绩效。
Your performance is...
你的绩效是……
How good or bad you do your job.
你工作做得好坏的程度。
Right.
对。
So you can have good performance or bad performance.
所以你可以有好的绩效或差的绩效。
Just how well you do your job.
就是你工作做得多好。
Perfect.
完美。
So now we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the first time and as always, it's going
现在我们准备第一次听对话，和往常一样，它会以正常语速播放，但你不用担心。
to be at a normal speed, but you don't have to worry about it.
因为我们会回来解释所有关键语言。
Because we'll come back and explain all the key language.
Now we're going to listen as two managers discuss the performance of one employee.
现在我们来听两位经理讨论一名员工的表现。
So Lauren, I just wanted to talk to you quickly about our new customer support representative,
劳伦，我想跟你简单谈谈我们新来的客服代表，
Jason Huntley.
杰森·亨特利。
Sure.
好的。
What's up?
怎么了？
Basically, I've got a few concerns about him.
基本上，我对他有些担忧。
And the bottom line is, I don't think he's a good fit for our company.
归根结底，我认为他不适合我们公司。
Okay.
好吧。
What makes you say that?
你为什么这么说？
I thought you were pleased with his overall performance.
我以为你对他的整体表现很满意。
Didn't you just tell me last week how impressed you were with his attitude?
你不是上周才告诉我你对他的态度印象深刻吗？
Yeah, his attitude is great, but he's really unreliable.
是啊，他的态度很好，但他真的很不可靠。
Sometimes he's really productive, but then other times...
有时候他效率很高，但其他时候……
Take last Tuesday, for instance.
就拿上周二来说吧。
He was 45 minutes late for our morning meeting.
他早会迟到了45分钟。
Well, I'm sure he had a perfectly good reason.
嗯，我肯定他有充分的理由。
But that's not the only thing.
但这还不是全部。
You know, he really doesn't have the best work ethic.
你知道，他的职业道德真的不太好。
I'm constantly catching him on MSN and Facebook when he should be talking to clients.
我经常发现他在应该跟客户通话的时候上MSN和Facebook。
Yeah, but come on, Jeff.
是啊，但拜托，杰夫。
As if you don't check Facebook at work.
好像你上班时不上Facebook似的。
Look, you hired this guy.
听着，这人是你招的。
We've invested a lot of time and money in his training.
我们在他的培训上投入了大量时间和金钱。
So now it's up to you to coach him.
所以现在该由你来指导他。
Make it work, Jeff.
想办法搞定，杰夫。
You would say that, wouldn't you?
你就会这么说，对吧？
He is your cousin.
他是你表弟。
What a jerk.
真是个混蛋。
Making me hire his stupid, useless cousin.
逼我雇他那个愚蠢无用的表弟。
So apparently, Lauren hired her cousin.
显然，劳伦雇了她的表弟。
Yes.
是的。
That's always a complicated situation working with family members.
和家人一起工作总是很复杂。
Yeah, it makes it really difficult for Jeff, doesn't it?
是啊，这让杰夫很难办，对吧？
Yeah, and apparently Jeff isn't very happy.
是的，显然杰夫很不高兴。
Well, let's look at the language he used to tell us that he's unhappy about this.
我们来看看他用来表达不满的语言。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, the first word on language takeaway today.
好的，今天语言要点的第一个词。
Unreliable.
不可靠的。
不可靠。
Unreliable.
So, let's listen to some examples of unreliable so then you can understand what it means.
那么，我们来听一些关于“不可靠”的例子，这样你就能理解它的意思了。
Example one.
例子一。
The trains here are so unreliable.
这里的火车太不可靠了。
They never arrive on time.
它们从不准时到达。
Example two.
例子二。
Thomas is pretty unreliable.
托马斯相当不可靠。
He never finishes his projects on time.
他从不按时完成他的项目。
Example three.
例子三。
You promised you would pick me up from work today.
你答应过今天下班来接我的。
You're so unreliable.
你太不可靠了。
We can understand that if someone is unreliable, we can't trust them to do their job, right?
我们可以理解，如果一个人不可靠，我们就不能信任他们完成工作，对吧？
Right.
对。
So you don't want to be unreliable.
所以你不想变得不可靠。
The opposite would be?
反义词是什么？
Reliable.
可靠。
You can trust them.
你可以信任他们。
Right.
对。
Our second word today.
我们今天的第二个词。
Productive.
高效。
When you're productive, it means that you accomplish your job, right?
当你高效时，意味着你完成了你的工作，对吧？
You do a lot of work in a short amount of time.
你在短时间内做了很多工作。
Productive.
高效。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
You want to be a productive employee.
你想成为一名高效的员工。
Yes.
是的。
Our third word, work ethic.
我们的第三个词，职业道德。
Work ethic.
职业道德。
So a person's work ethic is that person's attitude towards work.
所以一个人的职业道德就是那个人对工作的态度。
Yes.
是的。
If they have a good work ethic, then they are always hardworking and they come to work
如果他们有良好的职业道德，那么他们总是勤奋工作，并且
early and they finish their jobs on time and they stay and do lots of overtime.
早早上班，按时完成工作，还会留下来加班很多。
So that's a good work ethic.
这就是良好的职业道德。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
And our last word, coach.
最后一个词，教练。
Coach.
教练。
When you coach an employee, you train them, right?
当你指导员工时，就是培训他们，对吧？
Yeah, you help that employee out by showing him or her how to do certain tasks.
是的，你通过向员工展示如何完成某些任务来帮助他们。
Or how to do their job better.
或者如何把工作做得更好。
Right.
对。
So we've got some great language to describe work performance.
所以我们有一些很好的语言来描述工作表现。
Let's listen to our dialogue a second time.
让我们再听一遍对话。
This time it'll be a little bit slower so you can understand these words and phrases
这次会慢一点，这样你就能更清楚地理解这些单词和短语。
a little bit more clearly.
更清楚一些。
So Lauren, I just wanted to talk to you quickly about our new customer support representative,
劳伦，我想和你简单谈谈我们新的客户支持代表，
Jason Huntley.
杰森·亨特利。
Sure.
当然。
What's up?
怎么了？
Basically, I've got a few concerns about him.
基本上，我对他有些担忧。
And the bottom line is I don't think he's a good fit for our company.
最重要的是，我认为他不适合我们公司。
Okay.
好吧。
What makes you say that?
你为什么这么说？
I thought you were pleased with his overall performance.
我以为你对他的整体表现很满意。
Didn't you just tell me last week how impressed you were with his attitude?
你不是上周才告诉我你对他的态度印象深刻吗？
Yeah, his attitude is great.
是的，他的态度很好。
But he's really unreliable.
但他真的很不可靠。
Sometimes he's really productive.
有时他效率很高。
But then other times...
但其他时候……
Take last Tuesday for instance.
就拿上周二来说吧。
He was 45 minutes late for our morning meeting.
他早会迟到了45分钟。
Well, I'm sure he had a perfectly good reason.
嗯，我肯定他有充分的理由。
But that's not the only thing.
但这还不是全部。
You know, he really doesn't have the best work ethic.
你知道，他的职业道德真的不是很好。
I'm constantly catching him on MSN and Facebook when he should be talking to clients.
我经常发现他在应该和客户通话的时候上MSN和Facebook。
Yeah, but come on, Jeff.
是啊，但拜托，杰夫。
As if you don't check Facebook at work.
好像你上班时不查Facebook似的。
Look, you hired this guy.
听着，这个人是你招的。
We've invested a lot of time and money in his training.
我们在他的培训上投入了很多时间和金钱。
So now it's up to you to coach him.
所以现在该由你来指导他了。
Make it work, Jeff.
想办法搞定，杰夫。
You would say that, wouldn't you?
你肯定会这么说，不是吗？
He is your cousin.
他是你表弟。
What a jerk.
真是个混蛋。
Make me hire your stupid, useless cousin.
逼我雇你那愚蠢无用的表弟。
All right, so if you noticed, a lot of useful phrases have come up.
好了，如果你注意到了，刚才出现了很多有用的短语。
So let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder, today we have three phrases.
流利度构建器，今天我们有三个短语。
That's right.
没错。
Three phrases that will help us make our point better.
三个能帮我们更好表达观点的短语。
The first one is bottom line.
第一个是“底线”。
The bottom line.
底线。
Let's listen to how this was used in the dialogue.
我们来听听它在对话中是怎么用的。
And the bottom line is, I don't think he's a good fit for our company.
而底线是，我认为他不适合我们公司。
So basically it means...
所以它基本上意思是……
Like the most important point.
就像最重要的点。
The most important point.
最重要的点。
Perfect.
完美。
The bottom line.
底线。
Our second word, overall.
我们的第二个词，“总体”。
Overall.
总体。
So this is the same as saying on the whole.
这和说“整体上”是一样的。
Right.
对。
So it's a big picture, how you would say.
所以它是大局观，可以这么说。
Yeah, in general.
是的，总的来说。
In general.
总的来说。
So his overall performance is good.
所以他的总体表现不错。
It means in general.
意思是总的来说。
His performance is good.
他的表现不错。
Perfect.
完美。
And our last phrase is very interesting because we can mix it up a little bit.
最后一个短语很有趣，因为我们可以稍微变通一下。
Yep.
嗯。
Perfectly good.
非常好。
So this is an interesting phrase because you can describe different objects in this way.
这是一个有趣的短语，因为你可以用这种方式描述不同的物体。
Yeah.
是的。
A perfectly good reason.
一个完全合理的理由。
A perfectly good car.
一辆完好的车。
A perfectly good computer.
一台完好的电脑。
So by the sounds of it, it's kind of like justifying.
听起来像是在辩解。
Yeah.
是的。
It's saying there's no problem with it.
意思是它没有问题。
There's no problem with it.
它没有问题。
Why would you throw it away if it's a perfectly good computer?
如果它是一台完好的电脑，你为什么要扔掉它？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Perfectly good.
完好的。
Okay.
好的。
So now we can listen to our dialogue a third time at a normal speed and now we're ready
现在我们可以以正常速度第三次听对话，我们已经准备好
to understand everything.
理解所有内容了。
So, Lauren, I just wanted to talk to you quickly about our new customer support representative,
劳伦，我想和你简单谈谈我们的新客服代表，
Jason Huntley.
杰森·亨特利。
Sure.
当然。
What's up?
怎么了？
Basically, I've got a few concerns about him and the bottom line is I don't think he's
基本上，我对他有些担忧，归根结底，我认为他不太
a good fit for our company.
适合我们公司。
Okay.
好吧。
What makes you say that?
你为什么这么说？
I thought you were pleased with his overall performance.
我以为你对他的整体表现很满意。
Didn't you just tell me last week how impressed you were with his attitude?
你上周不是还告诉我你对他的态度印象深刻吗？
Yeah.
是的。
His attitude is great, but he's really unreliable.
他的态度很好，但他真的很不可靠。
Sometimes he's really productive, but then other times, take last Tuesday for instance,
有时他效率很高，但其他时候，比如上周二，
he was 45 minutes late for our morning meeting.
他早会迟到了45分钟。
Well, I'm sure he had a perfectly good reason.
嗯，我肯定他有完全合理的理由。
But that's not the only thing.
但这还不是全部。
You know, he really doesn't have the best work ethic.
你知道，他的职业道德真的不太好。
I'm constantly catching him on MSN and Facebook when he should be talking to clients.
我经常发现他在应该和客户通话的时候上MSN和Facebook。
Yeah, but come on, Jeff.
是啊，但拜托，杰夫。
As if you don't check Facebook at work.
好像你上班时不查Facebook似的。
Look, you hired this guy.
听着，是你雇了这个人。
We've invested a lot of time and money in his training.
我们在他的培训上投入了大量时间和金钱。
So now it's up to you to coach him.
所以现在由你来指导他。
Make it work, Jeff.
想办法搞定，杰夫。
搞定它，杰夫。
You would say that, wouldn't you?
你肯定会这么说，不是吗？
He is your cousin.
他是你表弟。
What a jerk.
真是个混蛋。
Making me hire your stupid, useless cousin.
逼我雇你那愚蠢又没用的表弟。
Okay.
好吧。
I hope everyone enjoyed our lesson today.
希望大家喜欢今天的课程。
We've found some really useful vocabulary for a business situation.
我们学到了一些在商务场合非常有用的词汇。
So go to our website at EnglishPod.com where you can leave all your questions and comments
请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在那里你可以留下所有问题和评论
and also find a lot of other resources.
并找到许多其他资源。
That's right.
没错。
Marco and I are always on the site and we're happy to answer your questions.
马可和我经常在网站上，很乐意回答你们的问题。
Right.
对。
So until then, it's goodbye.
那么，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。